export const data = [
    {
        "id" : 1,
        "prompt" : "A 23 y/o female patient presents to the clinic with profuse frothy yellowish to greenish coloured vaginal discharge. The patient reports being sexually active with multiple partners and does not always use protection. Her family doctor performs a pelvic exam and notes the presence of a strawberry cervix. A vaginal wet mount is done and a sample is sent for PCR. The lab reports the presence of an anaerobic parasitic flagellated protozoa. The most likely pathogen in this case presentation is best treated with which of the following antimicrobials?",
        "choices": [
            "Azithromycin",
            "Ceftriaxone + doxycycline",
            "Doxycycline", 
            "Metronidazole",
            "Penicillin G"],
        "correct": "Metronidazole",
        "tags":["ABX","easy","Ob/Gyn","Infectious","PD"]
    },
    {
        "id" : 2,
        "prompt" : "A 24 y/o female patient presents to the clinic with dysuria and abnormal vaginal bleeding that is not associated with her menstrual period. A pelvic exam is performed and a swab is sent to the lab for PCR testing. The results report a Gram negative intracellular bacteria. The most likely pathogen in this case presentation is best treated with which of the following antimicrobials?",
        "choices": [
            "Azithromycin",
            "Ceftriaxone + doxycycline",
            "Cefoxitin + doxycycline", 
            "Metronidazole",
            "Penicillin G"],
        "correct": "Azithromycin",
        "tags":["ABX","medium","Ob/Gyn","Infectious","PD"]
    },
   {
        "id" : 3,
        "prompt" : "A 28 y/o male presents to the clinic with a fever, myalgia, pain in multiple joints, a painless skin lesion on his right hand, and tenosynovitis (inflammation of the tendon and its synovial sheath). A sexual history is taken and he reports being sexually active with multiple partners and rarely uses protection.  The doctor performs a physical exam and sends a blood sample to be cultured. The lab reports a gram negative diplococcus. The most likely pathogen in this case presentation is best treated with which of the following antimicrobials?",
        "choices": [
            "Azithromycin",
            "Ceftriaxone + doxycycline",
            "Clindamycin + gentamicin", 
            "Metronidazole",
            "Penicillin G"],
        "correct": "Ceftriaxone + doxycycline",
        "tags":["ABX","medium","Ob/Gyn","Infectious","PD"]
    },  
    {
        "id" : 4,
        "prompt" : "A 32 y/o male presents to the clinic with a painless chancre on his penis. He is asked about his sexual history and he reports having multiple partners and does not use protection. A sample is cultured, but nothing grows. The most likely pathogen in this case presentation is best treated with which of the following antimicrobials?",
        "choices": [
            "Azithromycin",
            "Ceftriaxone + doxycycline",
            "Cefoxitin + doxycycline", 
            "Metronidazole",
            "Penicillin G"],
        "correct": "Penicillin G",
        "tags":["ABX","easy","Ob/Gyn","Infectious","PD"]
    },
  {
        "id" : 5,
        "prompt" : "A 27 y/o female presents to the ER with severe lower abdominal pain, fever (T 39 \u00b0C), and vomiting. The pain is localized to the right lower quadrant. Thinking that it is appendicitis, general surgery is consulted to book an appendectomy. However, an astute medical student asks the patient about her sexual history and if she has had any UTI symptoms. The patient recalls having a new sexual partner and has recently experienced dysuria and an unusual discharge from her vagina. With this new information, your current working diagnosis can be treated with which of the following interventions:",
        "choices": [
            "Appendectomy",
            "Clindamycin + gentamicin",
            "Metronidazole",
            "Vancomycin",
            "Piperacillin-tazobactam"],
        "correct": "Clindamycin + gentamicin",
        "tags":["ABX","hard","Ob/Gyn","Infectious","PD","ED"]
    },
{
        "id" : 6,
        "prompt" : "Which of the following correctly describes the mechanism of action of levonorgestrel as an emergency contraceptive?",
        "choices": [
            "Blocks LH surge, alters fallopian tube contractility and inhibits sperm binding to the zona pellucida",
            "Causes uterine contractions that prevents implantation of blastocyst and abortion of any implanted blastocysts",
            "Interferes with follicle rupture", 
            "Releases ions that are toxic to sperm and ova, and interferes with fallopian tube and myometrial contractility"],
        "correct": "Blocks LH surge, alters fallopian tube contractility and inhibits sperm binding to the zona pellucida",
        "tags":["PD","MoA","easy","Ob/Gyn"]
    }, 
{
        "id" : 7,
        "prompt" : "Which of the following is the primary mechanism of action of ethinyl estradiol in a combined hormonal contraceptive?",
        "choices": [
            "Cervical mucus thickening that is impervious",
            "Decrease tubal peristalsis",
            "Formation of a non-receptive endometrium", 
            "Inhibit FSH release - decrease follicular recruitment and prevent ovulation",
            "Inhibit LH release - prevent ovulation"],
        "correct": "Inhibit FSH release - decrease follicular recruitment and prevent ovulation",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Ob/Gyn"]
    }, 
{
        "id" : 8,
        "prompt" : "Which of the following correctly describes a mechanism behind OCP-based treatment of hirsutism/acne?",
        "choices": [
            "Acts as an antagonist of the androgen and mineralocorticoid receptor",
            "Decrease in FSH will lead to less testosterone production",
            "Increase in SHBG will bind more testosterone, therefore decreasing free testosterone levels", 
            "Increase in SHBG will increase the levels of progesterone, therefore causing more androgen receptor inhibition"],
        "correct": "Increase in SHBG will bind more testosterone, therefore decreasing free testosterone levels",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Ob/Gyn"]
    },
{
        "id" : 9,
        "prompt" : "How does clomiphene citrate work in treating PCOS?",
        "choices": [
            "Blocks estrogen feedback by inhibiting estrogen receptor and hypothalamus and pituitary, leading to increased FSH to increase ovulation probability",
            "Blocks estrogen feedback by decreasing estrogen production by inhibiting aromatase, thus leading to increased FSH to increase ovulation probability",
            "Blocks estrogen feedback by inhibiting estrogen receptor and hypothalamus and pituitary, leading to increased LH to increase ovulation probability", 
            "Blocks estrogen feedback by decreasing estrogen production by inhibiting aromatase, thus leading to increased LH to increase ovulation probability"],
        "correct": "Blocks estrogen feedback by inhibiting estrogen receptor and hypothalamus and pituitary, leading to increased FSH to increase ovulation probability",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Ob/Gyn"]
    },
{
        "id" : 10,
        "prompt" : "A 28 y/o female with a history of T2DM and a raised BMI presents to the clinic with oligomenorrhea and facial hair growth. She and her husband have been trying to have a child for over two years. A comprehensive diagnostic workup is performed and she is diagnosed with PCOS. The patient is open to lifestyle changes and the doctor prescribes metformin for her PCOS. Is metformin an appropriate choice of therapy, why or why not?",
        "choices": [
            "No, metformin has little effect on the hypothalamic-pituitary-ovarian axis",
            "No, metformin reduces insulin levels, which will increase LH activity on theca cells",
            "No, metformin increases insulin levels, which will increase the potentiation of LH activity on theca cells", 
            "Yes, metformin reduces insulin levels, which will decrease the potentiation of LH activity on theca cells",
            "Yes, metformin increases insulin levels, which will inhibit LH activity on theca cells"],
        "correct": "Yes, metformin reduces insulin levels, which will decrease the potentiation of LH activity on theca cells",
        "tags":["PD","medium","MoA","Ob/Gyn","Endocrinology"]
    },      
]